# Dénes Bán, PhD

⊠ mr@zealot.hu

**1** 06-70/459-6622

linkedin.com/in/bandenes



# **Summary**

Senior software engineer with 8 years of experience in various programming environments (C++, Java, Full-stack Web, Python, Automation scripting). Proven track record of excellent writing and communication skills (publications, documentation, conferences and talks, both in English and Hungarian). Focusing on static source code analysis, maintainable system architecture design, software quality and machine learning; aiming to transition fully into data science. Vocal proponent of remote work and financial independence, avid reader of science fiction and fantasy, constant listener of neurofunk.

### **Experience**

#### Postdoctoral Research Fellow @ SZTE

April 2018 – Present

- Bug prediction through deep neural networks
- Data science related tasks in the Python ecosystem

### **Software Engineer** @ SZTE

June 2012 - April 2018

- Static source code analysis and data schema design
- Syntactic tree building and metric calculations
- · Software quality related research
- Tech lead on a medical internal accounting solution
- Senior developer on an industrial ERP system
- In charge of multiple refactoring and automating efforts

# Web Developer @ Ingatlannet.hu

February 2010 - May 2012

- · Developing and expanding the GUI and backend
- Maintaining the admin pages and databases
- Managing virtual machines, backups and configurations

# System Designer @ SkyPlusz

May 2011 - December 2011

- · Implementing a financial administrative webinterface
- Designing the system architecture by analyzing business requirements

### **Education** @ SZTE

### **Doctor of Philosophy (PhD)**

Computer Science Summa Cum Laude 2014 – 2018

### **Master of Science (MSc)**

Software Information Technology

Grade: 4.95 2012 – 2014

### **Bachelor of Science (BSc)**

Software Information Technology

Talent Management Program

Grade: 4.95 2009 – 2012

### **Honors**

- Fellowship of the Republic × 2
- Fellowship of the City of Szeged
- Pro Ingenio Award